Guide to the Cayuga Lodge papers, 1937-1997.
Cayuga Lodge papers
- William Ballagh Cornell Class of 1937 files
  - Packet sent to early members of Llenroc Lodge, 12/1/1987 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill and Jane Ballagh congratulating them on the birth (11/16/1941) of Donald William Ballagh, 11/28/1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Dr. Ott to Bill Ballagh regarding financial/employee problems in the Dining Room, 5/6/1942 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Form letter from Dr. Ott to residents of Cayuga Student Residence Assn. on the benefits of the Lodge and the need for continued recruiting of new members, 7/14/1942 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Circular letter from Dr. Ott on his declining eyesight and installation of the “Talking Book Machine” in his library. He requested letters from friends, undated, circa 6/1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - From letter from Hugh Moran to Fellow Members of Cayuga Student Residence Assn. announcing the retirement of Dr. Ott and appointment of officers of the Board of Trustees under the war-time powers of the Association Constitution amendment, 1942, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Form letter from Hugh Moran dated 8/30/1945 to “All the Old Crowd at Cayuga Lodge” announcing Dr. Ott had moved from the Lodge and in with his daughter and two grandchildren on their farm. Mr. Moran was very hopeful for a prosperous future for the Lodge. He attached Lee Whitford’s extensive report to the Permanent Members, 8/8/1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Member Group Photo signed by members on back in position on photo, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Form letter from Tom Ballagh to Permanent Members requesting information, list of Permanent Members names and addresses for distribution is attached, 12/1/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - William Ballagh Memoir, 11/19/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Mrs. F.B. Rosevear, 2/1/1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Bill Oden, 2/3/1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Postcard from Bob Nagel acknowledging receipt of Llenroc Lodge packet (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Bob Nagel, 1/7/1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Jess Young, 12/12/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Russ Martin, 12/17/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    (A quote from his letter: “My last recollection of Dr. Ott came in the 1950’s. I knew that he was very ill, and while presiding at a meeting of the Board of Directors at the Lodge, we received word that he had passed away. It was a sad moment for all of us.”)
  - Letter from Art Schuyler, 1/3/1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Dan Kurshan, 12/30/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Bruce Cormack, 12/13/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Roy E. “Jim” Woodbury, 12/4/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Note from Dick Kline, ’64, 12/19/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Dick Kline, ’64, 12/19/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Leigh Whitford, 12/13/1987 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Francis T. Jones, 2/2/1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    With attachments of original request and copy of Who’s Who in Mineral Names